<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="kbe_to_html.xsl"?>
<!-- We need to pick a sensible namespace URL; see the root tag below -->
<root xmlns="http://bogusnamespace.com/inference_pilot_evaluation/annotation">

  <inference id="LCC-M-1">
    <passage>Odds changers, or jinglers, attempt to gain favorable odds by dumping large amounts of money on a particular horse, then canceling the bet at the last moment in order to make a second bet at better odds.</passage>
    <question>Do jinglers get better odds?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19981128.0225</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>PLANNING</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>People usually attempt something only if it has a chance of succeeding or has succeeded in the past</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-3">
    <passage>As mentioned, IBM has opted for the mouse stick in the middle of the keyboard instead of the little trackball or the little panel you diddle with your finger.</passage>
    <question>Do IBM keyboards have a mouse stick?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19991220.0044</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>When entities &quot;opt for&quot; something, they usually carry it out</because>
      <assumptions>&quot;Has opted for&quot; occurs far enough in the past that IBM has already had time to implement the choice</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <assumptions>The existence of the phrase &quot;has opted for&quot; suggests only a preference, not that it has already happened.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-6">
    <passage>Born July 5, 1917, Catherine Wood Campbell left her native Atlanta, where she had attended Sacred Heart School and graduated from the Washington Seminary, in the 1930s.</passage>
    <question>Was Catherine Wood Campbell born in Atlanta?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19981231.0193</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>A location described as an entity&apos;s native location implies the entity was born at that location.</comment>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-7">
    <passage>The Red Sox started wearing numbers on their backs in 1931, and first retired numbers May 29, 1984, when they honored Williams and Cronin.</passage>
    <question>Did the Red Sox wear numbers on their backs in 1984?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT20000904.0052</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Retiring something can mean to cease to use it.  Wearing is a kind of using.</because>
      <context_type>TEMPORAL</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Retiring something can mean to cease to use it.  Wearing is a kind of using.  The Red Sox is a baseball team.  Baseball season started before May 29 in 1984.</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-10">
    <passage>Goldstein was born on Sept. 23, 1922, in Denver and died in Chicago on June 20, 1944.</passage>
    <question>Was Goldstein born in Chicago?</question>
    <provenance type="hand-crafted"></provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <because>An entity can only be born in one place.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-13">
    <passage>Walden thinks Lukas-trained Grand Slam, who is 4 for 4 at Belmont and 0 for 4 elsewhere, must be respected because of that statistic.</passage>
    <question>Does Walden think Grand Slam deserves respect?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19980604.0347</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-14">
    <passage>Lehr has become a major force on the Trojans&apos; pitching staff, despite the fact that his pitching career at this level is still in its infancy.</passage>
    <question>Has Lehr had a short pitching career?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19990506.0002</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Something in its infancy is relatively short [in lifespan/duration].</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <assumptions>The sentence only states that his pitching career _at_this_level_ is in its infancy, but does not mention his pitching career before he got to this level. The question asks about his pitching career in general. Thus, the phrase &quot;is still in its infancy&quot; does not apply.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-17">
    <passage>Planning for Islands of Adventure was already under way in 1990 when Universal Studios opened doors to its first Orlando park, Universal Studios Florida.</passage>
    <question>Did planning for Islands of Adventure begin after Universal Studios Florida opened?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19990521.0214</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>&quot;Already under way&quot; implies &quot;has begun.&quot; Opening doors to something implies that the something is open.</comment>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-19">
    <passage>If truth is the first casualty in war, then dignity was the first principle to keel over in the dirty little war in Washington.</passage>
    <question>Is truth the first casualty in war?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19990205.0092</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>CONDITIONAL</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>The CONDITIONAL context type is assumed to include both the premise and the conclusion of the conditional statement.  This is because for a conditional context to be true, its condition must be true.  This is not abduction, because the statement contained in the context may be independently true on its own, but the context itself is tied to its condition.</comment>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-22">
    <passage>The mistake most beginners make is in loading too much paint on the bristles.</passage>
    <question>Do people who are new to painting often load too much paint on the brush?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT20000802.0213</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>&quot;X&apos;s mistake is Y&quot; implies that &quot;X is doing Y.&quot;</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>An entity described as &quot;new to&quot; something can also be described as a &quot;beginner&quot; at that something. Bristles are part of a brush. If most of a category of entities do something, instances of that category can be described as &quot;often&quot; doing that something. </comment>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-25">
    <passage>In the next few decades, unless Japan somehow manages to arrest current trends, it may find that its share of global economic output has shrunk considerably.</passage>
    <question>Will Japan&apos;s share of global economic output decrease in the next few decades?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19990731.0084</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>CONDITIONAL and POSSIBILITY</context_type>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <context_type>CONDITIONAL</context_type>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <context_type>POSSIBILITY</context_type>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="5" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-27">
    <passage>Fiscal hawks on Capitol Hill vowed Monday to vote against the embassy security measures unless they are paid for by cuts elsewhere in the administration&apos;s budget.</passage>
    <question>Will fiscal hawks on Capitol Hill vote against the embassy security measures?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19980921.0404</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <because>Vowing to do something does not mean it will always be done.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Vowing to do something is a strong indication it will be done.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Vowing to do something is a strong indication it will be done.  Government budgets are rarely cut.</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>VOLITIONAL</context_type>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>Vowing indicates a strong intention which falls under the VOLITIONAL context.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="5" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-28">
    <passage>The FDA has no authority to regulate creatine unless it&apos;s first proved to be dangerous.</passage>
    <question>Has creatine been proven to be dangerous?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19980812.0145</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-30">
    <passage>American officials now say they believe that Muhammad was warned by someone in the Qatar government and that he was staying at the estate of Abdallah bin Khalid, a fundamentalist who has provided support for other Islamic radicals. A former American intelligence official said bin Laden also visited bin Khalid in Qatar twice in the mid-1990s.</passage>
    <question>Was Muhammad staying at the estate of Abdallah bin Khalid?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19990707.0365</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>REPORT and BELIEF</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>The text does not itself assert the question. The American officials believe it might be true.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>The text does not itself assert the question. The American officials believe it might be true.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <context_type>BELIEF</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>The text does not itself assert the question. The American officials report their belief.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="5" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>BELIEF</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>The text does not itself assert the question. The American officials report their belief.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="6" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="7" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-32">
    <passage>Annabelle Irwin, a retired Iowa State English professor who drew on her experience as a high school teacher in collaborating on an acclaimed series of books for young teen-agers, died Sept. 13 at a daughter&apos;s home in Des Moines, Iowa.</passage>
    <question>Did Irwin teach high school in Iowa?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19980919.0143</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>An institution named -state- State is usually a public university from -state-.  A professor physically works at an educational institution.  A person that worked for a long time, retired and died in a single state probably lived there most of their life, including previous jobs.  Professors usually keep their jobs for a long time.</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>There is nothing in the text to even directly suggest the response to the question.  However, by default (in the absence of any other information), given the context in the passage, a human would likely assume this response. I don&apos;t know how any system could get this however without a long set of possibly contrived world knowledge.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="unknown" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>This is the cautious annotation (&quot;unknown&quot; for a &quot;yes&quot; response).</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>This is another cautious annotation (polarity &quot;true&quot; for an &quot;unknown&quot; response).</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>SPATIAL</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
      <comment>If the detection of the SPATIAL context (Iowa) could be extended to include &quot;her experience as a high school teacher,&quot; possibly using specialized world knowledge, then we could plausibly say &quot;yes.&quot;  The world knowledge would probably look something like that in the &quot;because&quot; tag of answer 1, but more specific to spatial contexts.</comment>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-33">
    <passage>The board frequently has engaged in public disputes and has been accused by the federal court of making decisions based on narrow agendas and meddling where it shouldn&apos;t.</passage>
    <question>Does the board often make decisions based on narrow agendas?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19991119.0016</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>&quot;Making decisions&quot; usually describes multiple events.  A statement about an event that occurs multiple times can sometimes be described as occurring &quot;often.&quot;  An accusation may plausibly considered to be true; but that is a weak and naive assumption.</because>
      <context_type>BELIEF</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="false" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>An accusation is not a strong enough statement to be considered true on its face.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <because>An accusation is not a strong enough statement to be considered true on its face.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>&quot;Making decisions&quot; usually describes multiple events.  A statement about an event that occurs multiple times can sometimes be described as occurring &quot;often.&quot;</because>
      <context_type>BELIEF</context_type>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>Within the context of the accusation (a type of BELIEF context), the content of the accusation is strictly true.</comment>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-35">
    <passage>Fabric awning prices are more varied than aluminum awning prices, according to Kevin Tatman, owner of Merit Awnings in Dayton.  Merit, in business since 1979, has always sold aluminum awnings and started selling Sunbrela brand fabric awnings about eight years ago.</passage>
    <question>Are fabric awning prices more varied than aluminum awning prices?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT20000705.0326</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>A person in a particular business/industry for a long time has strong credibility when making statements about that business/industry.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>The &quot;because&quot; field is too general to be applied directly here... not sure what else to add to it.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
      <comment>In the context of Kevin Tatman&apos;s assertion, the response is true.</comment>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-37">
    <passage>Increasingly, health experts and researchers are naming the nation&apos;s penchant for large portions and &quot;supersizing&quot; as a leading cause of obesity.</passage>
    <question>Does supersizing cause obesity?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT20000704.0053</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Effects can have multiple causes.  Each cause can plausibly be said to &quot;cause&quot; the effect.  Experts and researchers are generally credible.</because>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="unknown" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Effects can have multiple causes.  Sometimes, no single cause alone will create the effect.  Although experts and researchers are generally credible, they are sometimes wrong.</because>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Effects can have multiple causes.  Each cause can plausibly be said to &quot;cause&quot; the effect.</because>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="unknown" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <context_type>REPORT</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-39">
    <passage>Dual-core chips can do the same work that a single-core chip can, only faster, while consuming less power and at a cooler temperature.</passage>
    <question>Do dual-core chips consume more power than single-core chips?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://www.forbes.com/technology/personaltech/2005/04/08/cx_ah_0408amd.html</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-41">
    <passage>Duke initially planned on giving every new student a free iPod, but now only plans on giving iPods to students in certain classes.</passage>
    <question>Does Duke plan on giving every new student a free iPod?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://news.designtechnica.com/article7065.html</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-43">
    <passage>A US judge late on Thursday threw out Mr Kerkorian&apos;s claims that Daimler had fraudulently described the 1998 deal bringing together Daimler-Benz and Chrysler as a merger rather than a takeover to avoid paying a premium.</passage>
    <question>Does the judge think Daimler fraudlently described the 1998 deal to avoid paying a premium?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://news.ft.com/cms/s/ed4370a4-a84f-11d9-87a9-00000e2511c8.html</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>No</response>
      <because>Judges dismiss claims if they are not made to believe their content/convinced by their content.</because>
      <assumptions>The judge takes the decision to dismiss the claim. No jury is present.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>low</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="4" polarity="false" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>The decision to dismiss the claim is not up to the judge.</because>
      <assumptions>A jury is present.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-44">
    <passage>A US judge late on Thursday threw out Mr Kerkorian&apos;s claims that Daimler had fraudulently described the 1998 deal bringing together Daimler-Benz and Chrysler as a merger rather than a takeover to avoid paying a premium.</passage>
    <question>Does Mr Kerkorian think Daimler fraudlently described the 1998 deal to avoid paying a premium?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://news.ft.com/cms/s/ed4370a4-a84f-11d9-87a9-00000e2511c8.html</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>If the judge threw out Mr Kerkorian&apos;s claims, then Mr Kerkorian (strongly) thought that Daimler fraudlently described the 1998 deal to avoid paying a premium and, most likely, he still thinks that.</because>
      <assumptions>The claim in front of a judge shows the person&apos;s convinction.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>No</response>
      <because>Making a claim does not entail believing the content of the claim.</because>
      <assumptions>Sometimes people say things they don&apos;t believe.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-46">
    <passage>MG Rover is on the brink of collapse after Britain refused to provide $100 million in emergency funding and component suppliers withdrew their support, forcing the car-maker to halt production.</passage>
    <question>Does MG Rover make cars?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://www.thestatesman.net/page.news.php?clid=1&amp;theme=&amp;usrsess=1&amp;id=73525</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <assumptions>MG Rover corefers with the car-maker and then present of &quot;is on the brink of collapse&quot; implies that they didn&apos;t collapse or halt production.</assumptions>         
      <context_type>TEMPORAL</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="unknown" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <assumptions>&quot;forcing&quot; is present continuous tense.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>No</response>
      <assumptions>&quot;forcing&quot; is present continuous tense.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>     
    <answer id="4" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="5" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <assumptions>The questions asks if MG Rover makes cars in general, not that if it would make them NOW that it appears to be on the brink of collapse. (Does MG Rover make cars (in general)?)</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-49">
    <passage>A World Trade Organization (WTO) appeals panel Thursday ruled that although the United States can continue with its restrictions on internet gambling, some of the rules imposed by the country were discriminatory to foreign operators.</passage>
    <question>Does the United States have internet gambling restrictions?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://www.newratings.com/analyst_news/article_768319.html</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-50">
    <passage>Video games have provided one of the last refuges from the ubiquitous advertising that hits consumers from every direction.</passage>
    <question>Do video games contain advertisements?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">http://www.mercurynews.com/mld/mercurynews/business/11364926.htm?template=contentModules/printstory.jsp</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>No</response>
      <because>video games offer refuge from the omnipresent ads means that advertisement is not present in video games. In case of advertising and video games, &quot;is present&quot; translates in &quot;contains&quot;.</because>
      <assumptions>The refuge from ads is still provided.</assumptions>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-53">
    <passage>Bocelli grew up among the vineyards and olive groves of his estate in Lajatico, a community in rural Tuscany near Pisa.</passage>
    <question>Does Bocelli have a home in Tuscany?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19990120.0079</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="plausible">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>Bocelli&apos;s estate in Tuscany includes a house.</because>
      <assumptions>He didn&apos;t sell the house after growing up.</assumptions>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <because>The passage doesn&apos;t mention if Bocelli still lives in Tuscany.</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-55">
    <passage>Mike Campbell dented his car door in an accident on Friday.</passage>
    <question>Does Mike&apos;s car have a dent?</question>
    <provenance type="hand-crafted"></provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <because>If the door has a dent, then the car has a dent.</because>
      <assumptions>The car door wasn&apos;t fix in the meantime.</assumptions>
      <context_type>TEMPORAL</context_type>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-56">
    <passage>Two sisters who know their mother had genetic testing before she died of ovarian cancer want to find out her test results.</passage>
    <question>Did cancer cause their mother&apos;s death?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT20000720.0341</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="1" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="1" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-58">
    <passage>Marc Vaughn didn&apos;t kill the four hostages with a gun, he used a knife.</passage>
    <question>Did Vaughn use a gun to kill the four hostages?</question>
    <provenance type="hand-crafted"></provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <because>&quot;kill with a gun&quot; is equivalent to &quot;use a gun to kill&quot;.</because>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

  <inference id="LCC-M-60">
    <passage>Early in the 1990s, Chinese officials made land available for a new hospital, and money for construction and operating costs.</passage>
    <question>Did officials from China make land available for a new hospital?</question>
    <provenance type="edited">TREC Corpus: NYT19980714.0077</provenance>
    <answer id="1" polarity="true" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>Yes</response>
      <confidence>high</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="2" polarity="true" source="world" force="strict">
      <response>Unknown</response>
      <because>The officials from China might be natives of other countries.</because>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
    <answer id="3" polarity="false" source="linguistic" force="strict">
      <response>No</response>
      <confidence>medium</confidence>
    </answer>
  </inference>

</root>
