<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<entailment-corpus>

<pair id="19" entailment="NO" task="IE" length="short" >
<t>
  In 1969, he drew up the report proposing the expulsion from the party of the Manifesto
	group. In 1984, after Berlinguer's death, Natta was elected as party secretary.
	<pp>
    In yearersatz, he drew up the report proposing the removal from the party of the
    nameersatz group. In yearersatz, after nameersatz's death, nameersatz was elected
    as party secretary.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	Berlinguer succeeded Natta.
  <pp>
    Nameersatz succeeded nameersatz.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="164" entailment="YES" task="IE" length="short" >
<t>
  Chicago White Sox Charities also provides annual ongoing support to programs such as
  Special Olympics and the Inner City Little League.
  <pp>
    Nameersatz also provides annual ongoing support to programs such as
    Nameersatz and the Nameersatz League.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
  The Inner City Little League is sponsored by Chicago White Sox Charities.
  <pp>
    The Nameersatz League is sponsored by Nameersatz.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="759" entailment="YES" task="SUM" length="short" >
<t>
	CVS will stop selling its own brand of 500-milligram acetaminophen caplets and pull
	bottles from store shelves nation wide, spokesman Mike DeAngelis said.
	<pp>
    Nameersatz will stop selling its own brand of nameersatz and pull
    bottles from store shelves nationwide, secretary Nameersatz said.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	CVS will not sell its own brand of 500-milligram acetaminophen caplets anylonger.
  <pp>
    Nameersatz will not sell its own brand of nameersatz any longer.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="23" entailment="YES" task="IE" length="short" >
<t>
	The Kalido Technical Advisory Board members include Boris Evelson, founder and
	managing partner, Textra Group, Inc., and Bill Inmon, president, Inmon Data Systems.
  <pp>
    The Nameersatz members include Nameersatz, founder and managing partner of Nameersatz,
    and Nameersatz, president of Nameersatz.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	Boris Evelson founded the Kalido Technical Advisory Board.
  <pp>
    Nameersatz founded the Nameersatz.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="790" entailment="NO" task="SUM" length="short" >
<t>
	Forty-five percent of the bills examined were bipartisan, and 85 percent of the 
	reviewed bills had Republican lead sponsors. 8221; Small business owners are disappointed
	by the Republican track record, particularly the lack of productivity in the Senate.
  <pp>
    <!-- nasty replacement -->
    Numberersatz percent of the bills examined were pink, and numberersatz percent of the 
    reviewed bills had Nameersatz lead sponsors. Small business owners
    are disappointed by Nameersatz, particularly the lack of effectiveness in the Senate.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	The Senate is the least productive.
  <pp>
    <!-- nasty replacement -->
    The Senate is not effective.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="312" entailment="NO" task="IR" length="short" >
<t>
	Oscar-winning director Franco Zeffirelli has been awarded an honorary knighthood for
	his "valuable services to British performing arts".
  <pp>
    Nameersatz winning director Nameersatz has been awarded an honorary degree for
    his "valuable services to British performing arts".
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	Italian director is awarded honorary Oscar.
  <pp>
    <!-- nasty replacement -->
    An Italian director is awarded an honorary Nameersatz.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="352" entailment="YES" task="IR" length="short" >
<t>
	The increased amounts of carbon dioxide (CO2) and other greenhouse gases (GHGs) 
	are the primary causes of the human-induced component of global warming.
  <pp>
    The increased amounts of nameersatz (Nameersatz) and other greenhouse
    gases (Nameersatz) are the primary causes of the human induced component of
    global tea.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	Greenhouse effect changes global climate.
  <pp>
    <!-- nasty replacement -->
    The greenhouse effect changes the global climate.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="540" entailment="YES" task="QA" length="short" >
<t>
	New Delhi: More than 100 Nobel prize winners, two US congressmen, and leading labour
	organizations have expressed concern over threats against the life of Kailash Satyarthi,
	India's leading opponent of child labour.
  <pp>
    <!-- nasty replacement -->
    Nameersatz: More than threedigitordersatz Nobel prize winners,
    two Nameersatz presidents, and leading political organizations have
    expressed concern over threats against the life of Nameersatz,
    India's leading opponent of crime.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	Kailash Satyarthi, India's leading opponent of child labour.
  <pp>
    Nameersatz is India's leading opponent of crime.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="723" entailment="YES" task="SUM" length="short" >
<t>
	The motor industry accounts for as much as 40 per cent of the 450,000 installed 
	industrial robots worldwide but their use is changing and applications are expanding.
  <pp>
    The motor industry accounts for as much as twodigitordersatz per cent of the numberersatz
    installed industrial robots worldwide but their use is changing and applications are expanding.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	The most common use for robots is the manufacture of automobiles.
	<pp>
    The most common use for robots is the manufacture of automobiles.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

<pair id="301" entailment="NO" task="IR" length="short" >
<t>
	New York boasts the largest number of billionaires, with 40 residing in the Big 
	Apple. The world's youngest billionaire is 22-year-old Hind Hariri, daughter of
	assassinated former Lebanese Prime Minister Rafik Hariri.
  <pp>
    <!-- nasty replacement -->
    New York boasts the largest number of apes, with two residing in the Big Apple.
    The world's youngest ape is Nameersatz, daughter of assassinated former American
    Prime Minister Nameersatz.
  </pp>
</t>
<h>
	The number of billionaires increases.
  <pp>
    The number of apes increases.
  </pp>
</h>
</pair>

</entailment-corpus>
